《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
本字幕由ZiMuZu原创翻译  最新下载请登录www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译 艾瑞卡   小酸奶!   小胖纸Amy   木浅   charcie
我怎么能允许他碰我
How I ever let him lay a hand on me...
翻译 Silence   DustD   盐湖凉开水   大K   草草
他滚出了你的生活我很高兴
I'm glad he's out of your life.
保持警惕  刺拳  刺拳
Keep that guard up-- jab, jab.
时间轴 风吹来的那片云
出拳  刺拳  刺拳  右拳
Lead... jab, jab, right.
你在做什么
What you doing?
阿尔弗雷德在教我如何打拳
Alfred's teaching me to fight.
我需要你带我去找派克兄弟
I need you to take me to the Pike Brothers.
那几个奈何岛的纵火犯吗
The firebugs from the Narrows?
后期 宝宝   校对 草草   总监 草草
我跟他们的小妹布莉姬特一起玩过
I used to hang with their sister, Bridgit.
你们好啊
Hey, boys.
我们需要最好的  而你们正巧就是
We need the best, and you guys are the best.
布莉姬  你刚刚升职了
Hey, Bridgy...you just got a promotion.
-哥谭市警局  -跑
- GCPD! - Run!
我抓到她了
I got her!
放下  放下
Drop it. Drop it.
请等一下  企鹅先生
One moment, Mr. Penguin.
母亲
Mother.
我什么都不知道
I don't know nothing...
你要去找盖勒文
You are going to go to Galavan.
等你打入了他的组织
Once you're inside his organization,
就找到我妈妈  救出她
you will find my mother and rescue her.
只要我们演得像
He'll buy it...
他就会相信
if we sell it right.
然后企鹅就发疯了
...and then Penguin just went crazy.
我从没见他那么疯狂过
I mean, like... crazier than I've ever seen him.
他说突袭点钞房是我在背后搞的鬼
He said it was me that set up the count house raid,
说我是叛徒  是内奸
said I was a traitor and a rat.
然后他拿着切肉刀朝我走来
Then he... he came at me with a cleaver.
我试图自卫  他却把我手砍了
I tried to protect myself and he did this.
变态混账
Sick bastard.
你是怎么逃走的
How'd you get away?
我流了很多血
There was a lot of blood.
很多
A lot.
他还准备继续砍我
And he... he tried to take another swing
但他滑了一跤  我就跑掉了
and he slipped and fell and so I just ran.
我跑啊跑
I ran and I ran and then...
然后我醒来就在医院了
the next thing I knew, I woke up in the hospital.
给我个机会  盖勒文先生
Give me a shot, Mr. Galavan.
我能证明自己的能力
Let me show you what I can do.
我也想帮你一把
Well, I'd like to help you out,
布奇
Butch,
但我这里已经有不少
but I already have several
办事得力而且双手健全的手下了
capable, two-handed thugs in my employ.
他们没我了解哥谭
They don't know Gotham like I do.
我很聪明  去打听一下就知道了
I got brains, you ask anyone.
女士们  你们觉得怎么样
What do you think, ladies?
我觉得他挺可爱的
I think he's cute.
像只伤心的大熊
Like a sad bear.
我想他说的是实话
I suppose he's telling the truth.
上次见到那小矮子时他就快崩溃了
The little man was cracking up last time I saw him.
他有次对我很坏
He was very mean to me once.
在我的公寓里挟持我
Held me hostage in my own apartment.
说了些很难听的话
Said some nasty things.
是不是  矮胖子
Isn't that right, stumpy?
没错  女士
That's right, ma'am.
我很抱歉
And I'm sorry for it.
你也知道  公事归公事
Business is business, you know?
拜托
Please.
让我为你效力吧  盖勒文先生
Let me work for you, Mr. Galavan.
我走投无路了
I got nobody else to turn to.
对了
Oh, yes!
我们可以给他按好玩的假肢
We can put cool things on his stump,
像刀和木槌之类的
like knives and mallets and stuff.
或者迷你链锯
How about a little tiny chain saw?
没错
Yes.
就这么定了
Well, that settles it.
欢迎加入  布奇
Welcome aboard, Butch.
谢谢你  先生
Thank you, sir.
好样的  议员先生
Bravo, Congressman.
好险
Well saved.
个头这么大  你身手倒挺敏捷
You really are quite spry for a big man.
你重新思考过你的立场了吗
Have you reconsidered your position?
-这次选举你会支持我吗  -会
- Can I count on your support this election? - Yes.
我会全力支持你
Yes, you have my full support.
太感谢你了
Thank you so much.
盖勒文
竞选市长
哥谭
第二季  第六集
不许动
Freeze!
我什么都没干  你为什么要追我
Man, I didn't do nothing! Why you chasing me?
昨晚有一名警官
A police officer died last night,
被一群疯狂的纵火犯杀了
killed by a firebug crew on a spree.
你是纵火犯吧
You're a firebug, aren't you?
不  伙计  我早就不干了
No, man! I been out of the game a long time!
-不要骗我  尼诺  -我发誓
- Don't lie to me, Nino! - I swear!
长官  这是违反警官行为条例的
Sir, that's a violation of officer conduct regs.
12小时前卢克·加勒特在我眼前被活活烧死
Luke Garrett burned to death in front of me 12 hours ago.
我自有分寸
I'll conduct myself as I see fit.
那群人中有个孩子
This crew's working with a kid.
一个女孩
A girl.
穿了一套自制的防火服
Wears a homemade fire suit.
我说真的  从没听说过有女纵火犯
Hey, for real! Never heard of a female firebug before.
那也太少见了  就像...
It's mad rare, like a...
独角兽什么的
like a unicorn or something.
长官
Sir?
巴恩斯警监说我们必须上报所有违规行为
Captain Barnes says we must report any infractions.
即使是我们的上级
Even by superior officers.
去上报吧
You do that.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我睡不着
Can't sleep.
我不知道该做什么好
I don't know what to do with myself.
这就是自由啊
That's the point of being free.
你想干什么就可以干什么
You get to do whatever the hell you want.
我要干什么
What am I gonna do?
我昨晚杀了一个人
I killed someone last night.
我不能回家
I can't go home.
我不能去找警察
I can't go to the police...
-你得离开哥谭  -怎么离开
- You gotta get out of town. - How?
我没有钱
I got no money.
这不是问题
No problem.
我们会搞到钱的
We'll get some.
你是说...犯罪吗
You mean, like, crime?
你还真是呆板
Man, you are square.
我想我也没得选
I guess I got no choice.
你为什么要帮我
Why are you helping me?
也许你让我想到了我自己
Maybe you remind me of me.
如果我也这么蠢
If I was a doofus.
这个犯罪...
This crime...
你究竟想做什么
what exactly you got in mind?
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen!
或者应该说是皮条客  妓女和窃贼们
Or should I say, pimps, hoes and thieves!
我今天可有好货
Do I have some product for you today!
你们看得满意吗
Do you like what you see?
来  让我听到你们的声音  你们满意吗
Come on, now let me hear you! Do you like what you see?!
好了  来看看  来看看
All right. Oh, check it out, check it out!
没错  漂亮又肮脏
Yeah, it's nice and it's dirty!
我要她
I want her!
每个女孩起价800美元
Bidding will start at $800. Apiece.
有出800美元的吗  来啊
Have we got $800? Come on!
850美元
$850!
那些女孩就这样被拿来卖吗
Those girls are for sale?
早告诉你这地方很变态了
Told you this place was freaky.
我们得帮她们
We need to help them.
我们是来帮你的
We're here to help you.
因为你杀了一个条子  记得吗
Cause you killed a cop, remember?
我们钱一到手就离开
We get the money, we go.
-但是...  -听着
- But... - Listen!
听我说
Listen.
你从楼梯上下去
You go down the stairs.
后门的锁坏了
The lock on the back door is busted.
我知道  因为是我弄坏的
I know, cause I busted it.
你进去之后
You go in,
等我开始行动
wait for me to make my move.
我怎么知道什么时候
How will I know when?
注意看
Pay attention.
戴酒红色帽子的男士以
Sold for $2,500 to the
2500美元的价格中标
gentleman in the burgundy hat!
过来  女士们
Come on, ladies.
为你们寻得了一个温馨的新家
Found you a nice new home!
你会非常满意的  非常非常满意
Oh, you'll be very satisfied. Very, very satisfied.
下一个出场
Next up!
她走下楼梯时好好瞧瞧
Check her out as she walks down the stage;
看看她多么优雅啊
see how graceful she is.
看看这一位
Look at this one!
这个起价900美元
I'm going to start the bidding here at $900!
有没有人出价900美元
Can I get $900?!
变态们
Hey, pervs!
这是抢劫
This is a robbery!
麦洛  杀了那小东西
Milo! Kill that punk.
她是和我一伙的
She's with me.
所有人立刻把现金放进袋子里
Now, each of you put all your cash in the bag.
不然呢
Or what?
我不怕你
I ain't scared of you.
好吧
All right.
还有人有异议吗
Anybody else got a problem?
我猜也没有了
Yeah, didn't think so.
对了
And for the record?
你们都令人恶心
All y'all suck.
救命
Help!
快  快  救我出去
Come on, come on! Get me out of here!
站住
Stop!
天哪
Oh, my God.
可不是  我们走
I know, right? Let's go.
要在我档案里记过  你开玩笑的吧
A note in my file? Are you serious?
我像是开玩笑的样子吗
Do I look like I'm joking?
警察不得打嫌犯  没有例外
We do not beat suspects! Ever!
我明白
I get it.
卢克是个好孩子
Luke was a good kid.
是我们把他从警校带出来  说他准备好了
We took him out of the academy, told him he was ready.
结果他死了
Now he's dead.
战争就会死人  你很清楚
You lose people in war. You know that.
别想错了  这就是场战争
Make no mistake, this is war.
但这并不意味着你或我有权违法
But that doesn't give you or me the license to break the law.
不能逾越底线
There's a line.
这是我摸爬滚打得来的教训
I learned that the hard way.
无意冒犯  长官  但这是哥谭
Respectfully, sir, this is Gotham.
有很多灰色地带
There are gray areas.
这也是我摸爬滚打得来的教训
I've learned that the hard way, too.
你为卢克报仇时
And did you even get a lead
找到线索了吗
while you were out avenging Luke?
-没有  长官  -没有是吧
- No, sir. - No, sir?
现在有了
Well, you got one now.
是酒水店老板提供的线索
Bodega owner called this in.
店里监控拍到的
His security camera caught it.
纵火的就是她
She's our firefly.
另一个还不知道是谁
We don't know who the other one is.
我知道
I do.
该死
Damn it.
集中注意力  集中注意力
Focus. Focus!
低头  低头
Head down! Head down!
注意力不集中会要了你的命  布鲁斯少爷
Distractions will be the death of you, Master Bruce.
警觉  保持警觉
Now, get on your toes. On your toes.
动起来
Move!
不要...
Well, don't...
像舞女跳舞似的
dance around like a bloody showgirl.
来吧
Come on.
好多了  好多了
That's better. Better.
来个左拳重击  来吧
Now, big left, big left. Go on!
抓住你了  你的对手
I got you. Now, your enemies,
会比这下流得多
are gonna fight a lot dirtier than that.
该死
Bloody hell.
不错嘛  布鲁斯少爷
Very good, Master Bruce.
你问过福克斯先生电脑的事了吗
Have you spoken to Mr. Fox about the computer?
问过了
That I have, yeah.
还要多久才能修好
How much longer until it's fixed?
好了就会告诉你的  耐心点
I'll tell you when it's done, won't I? Patience.
我快没耐心了  阿尔弗雷德  我准备好了
I'm tired of patience, Alfred. I'm ready to begin.
你有没有准备好  我说了算  布鲁斯少爷
I'll tell you when you're ready, Master Bruce.
我已经准备好了  我很清楚
I'm ready now. I know I am.
另外  跟你说
By the way, by the way,
茜尔薇小姐打来电话
Miss Silver called.
她约你今晚去吃饭
She wants you to go for dinner this evening.
茜尔薇找我吗
Silver called?
就说嘛
Told ya.
没准备好
Not ready.
继续来
Let's go.
他就这样突然离开了哥谭
Well, he just up and moved out of town.
不仅无礼  也不顾及他人感受
It was rude and inconsiderate
汤姆·多尔蒂就是这种人
and perfectly in character for Tom Dougherty.
你就不好奇他的去向吗
Do you ever wonder where he went?
他就算死在水沟里我也不在乎
He could be dead in a ditch for all I care.
-柯丽丝汀  -我不是开玩笑  他
- Kristen. - And I mean it, too. He, um...
他对我不太好
he wasn't very nice to me.
太糟了
That's awful.
-我很遗憾  -谢谢
- I'm so sorry. - Thank you.
但是  结果也挺好
But... it all worked out for the best.
是啊  你和爱德似乎挺合得来
I know. You and Ed seem to be getting along.
他又温柔又善良
He is so gentle and kind.
有点太温柔了
Almost too gentle.
我认为一个男人需要有点
I-I think a man needs to have a little...
有点火气  有点危险  你不觉得吗
a little fire, a little danger in him, don't you think?
这未必吧
Oh, I don't know about that.
有时我觉得
And sometimes I-I feel like
他有事瞒着我
he's holding something back from me.
有秘密吗
Like a secret?
不知道
I don't know.
我只是  希望他能更加敞开心扉一些
I just... I guess I just wish he would open up a little more.
早上好
Good morning.
柯林格小姐  汤普金斯小姐
Miss Kringle, Miss Thompkins.
三只脚的牛该叫什么
What do you call a three-legged cow?
-我不会猜这个  -瘦牛肉[歪脚牛]
- I am terrible... - Lean beef.
或是晚餐  去我家
Or supper. At my place.
爱德
Ed.
红发人之间不打诳语
Ginger to ginger, we both know
你知道塞琳娜·凯尔在哪
you know where Selina Kyle's at,
你告诉我吧  省了不必要的麻烦
so why don't you tell me now and save us the hassle.
谁是塞琳娜·凯尔
Who's Selina Kyle?
小猫
Cat.
Cat?
艾薇
Look, Ivy,
要我打电话给儿童院
want me to call the children's home
叫他们现在来接你吗
and have 'em come get you now?
还是要我去买糖果
Or should I get a candy bar
然后忘记叫人看着你呢
and forget to have someone watch you?
糖果
Candy bar.
没结果
I struck out.
我问过的流浪儿都说没见过塞琳娜
None of the street kids I talked to have seen Selina.
别紧张  你哈维叔叔已经帮你搞定了
Relax. Your Uncle Harvey has you covered.
她住在詹金斯街一间废弃单人房里
She's in a squat off Jenkins. Condemned SRO.
我知道那地方
I know it.
上次我们见到这小妞
Last time we saw this chick,
她拿枪指着我们
she had a shotgun pointed at us.
也许你该带上法西斯青年团
Maybe you should take the Fascist Youth, huh?
不用
Nah.
是塞琳娜的话  最好还是动静小点
With Selina, it's best to go quietly.
等你到了大巴站
When you get to the bus station,
坐第一班南下的车
take the first bus south.
一口气坐到终点
Stay on till the end of the line.
然后怎么办
Well, what do I do then?
你有的是钱了  想干什么都可以
You got plenty of money. You can do what you like.
谢谢你
Thank you.
为我做的一切
For everything.
你真是我的好朋友
You've been a really good friend.
我也分到钱了呀
I got my cut.
没什么的
No biggie.
布莉姬特  你赶紧跑
Bridgit, you need to run.
布莉姬特  跑  快跑
Bridgit, run! Run! Run!
不  塞琳娜  不要
No... Selina! No!
塞琳娜
Selina!
不  不要
No! No!
救救我
Help me!
把手举起来
Hands in the air!
把枪放下
Drop the gun.
我才不放
Like hell I will.
你女朋友呢
Where's your girlfriend?
谁呀
Who?
你们俩都被监控拍到了
We got both of you on tape.
不知道你在说什么  戈登
Don't know what you're talking about, Gordon.
她烧了六栋大楼
She's burnt down half a dozen buildings.
杀了个警察  同伴选的不怎么样啊  丫头
Killed a cop. You're running with a bad partner, kid.
你不明白
You don't understand.
她是被人逼着干那些事的
She was forced to do all of that.
好吧
Okay.
那让我帮她
Let me help her.
她是谁  是谁在逼她干这些事
Who is she? Who's forcing her to do this?
现在外面有很多愤怒的警察
Look, there's a lot of angry cops out there.
她被发现就会被击毙  除非我先找到她
She's gonna get shot on sight, unless I get to her first.
她名字叫布莉姬特·派克
Her name is Bridgit Pike.
她哥哥们把她抓回去了
Her brothers took her back.
乔和凯尔·派克
Joe and Cale Pike.
他们  绑架了她
They, like... kidnapped her.
当初就是他们逼她去纵火的
They're the ones who made her start burning stuff in the first place.
那个警察的死是他们的错
It's their fault the cop died.
派克兄弟
The Pike brothers?
他们为什么要烧韦恩集团的大楼
Why'd they burn down Wayne Enterprises' buildings?
谁付钱让他们干的
Who paid them?
我怎么会知道派克兄弟的动机
Why the hell should I know why the Pikes do anything?
他们是疯子
They're freakin' nuts.
他们把布莉姬特当奴隶  铐在墙上
They treated Bridgit like a slave, chained her to the wall.
这惹恼了你  所以你才这么全副武装吗
And you're angry about it. Is that why you're armed?
你要去找派克兄弟的麻烦
You're gonna go after the Pikes?
救你的朋友吗
Rescue your friend?
不是
No.
那就是是了
That's a yes.
你会害死你的朋友和你自己的
Look, you're gonna get your friend and yourself killed.
让我来对付派克兄弟
Let me handle the Pikes.
无意冒犯  吉姆
No offense, Jim,
但是我觉得我比你的胜算更大
but I like my chances better than yours.
为什么要介入
Why get involved?
为什么要涉险
Why risk your neck?
这女孩是你的什么人
Who is this girl to you?
什么人也不是  只不过...
No one. Just...
是个邻家女孩而已
a girl in the neighborhood.
我向你保证
I give you my word.
我会尽一切努力保证她的安全
I will do everything I can to keep her safe.
但是你不能插手
But you have to stay out of it.
告诉我她在哪
Tell me where she is.
我去
Damn.
她这儿有六千美元
She's got six grand here.
小布莉姬玩起大人游戏了
Little Bridgy put on her big girl pants.
你们可以都拿走  我不在乎
You can take all of it. I don't care.
我当然会拿走
Oh, I'm taking it.
问题不在这儿  问题是
That's not the issue. The issue
你觉得可以就这么甩掉哥哥们吗
is you thinking it's cool to just ditch your brothers, hmm?
哎哟
Oh, snap.
布莉姬要倒霉了
Bridgit's gonna get it.
乔  求你
Joe, please.
你想过我们吗
Did you even think about us, hmm?
你有想过我们的感受吗
Did you even think how we would feel?
不要  别
No, don't!
乔  我没别的意思
Joe, I didn't mean anything by it!
我是个敏感的男人  而你伤了我的感情
I'm a sensitive guy, and you hurt my feelings.
没有家人  你还剩下什么
You know, without family, what do you got?
你什么都没有了  是不是
You-you got nothin', right?
你想重新成为这家的人吗
You want to be part of the family again?
我说
I said...
你想重新成为这家的人吗
do you feel like being part of this family again?
想
Yes!
该死
Damn!
该死  真疼
Damn, that hurts.
布莉姬回来了
Bridgit's back.
如果你再做这种事  我就杀了你
If you try anything like that again, I'll kill you,
我还会扒了那只小贱猫的皮  听到了吗
and I'll skin that little cat bitch, too. You hear me?
你逃不掉了
You're never leaving.
听到了
Yes.
很好
Good.
给我们做晚饭去
Go make our supper.
好了  都收拾起来吧
All right, let's pack it up.
我的天
Dear me.
一个木槌
A mallet.
这个  挺有用的
That's, um... useful.
别提了
Don't even start.
告诉我你带来了好消息
Tell me you bring good news.
我打进去了
I'm in.
他们非常信任我
I'm in good.
还有呢  还有呢
And? And?!
我正在打听呢
I'm asking questions.
但这太危险了
But it's dangerous.
如果我问得太多  盖勒文就会怀疑我的
If I push too hard, Galavan'll be onto me.
我告诉过你  他非常精明
I told you, he's a smart guy.
看着我  布奇
Look at me, Butch.
你是我的仆人吗
Are you my servant?
是的
Yes.
你愿意服从我的一切命令吗
Do you obey me in all things?
是的
Yes.
那你为什么找这么多借口
Then why do you bring me excuses?
去找我母亲
Go find my mother.
不然我把你的另一只手也砍下来
Before I chop off your other hand.
遵命  老大
Yes, boss.
用力点
Come on. Harder.
用力  乔
Come on, Joe.
你要干什么
What are you gonna do,
杀了我们吗
kill us?
没错
Yep.
上帝啊
Oh, God!
我去检查另一个房间
I'll check the other room.
安全
Clear!
她不在这里
She's not here.
该死
Damn.
一股香香的烤肉味儿  真闹心
I hate how it smells like good barbecue.
贱人
Bitch.
布洛克
Bullock, hey!
干吗
What?!
他把我吓了一跳
Scared the hell out of me!
这下他死了
And now he's dead.
干得漂亮  布洛克
Nice work, Bullock.
是吗  是我把他踢死了吗
Oh, yeah. My kicks did it?
也许是因为他都烤成卷饼了
Maybe it's because he's fried like a taquito!
这不是我的错
It's not on me.
看来塞琳娜说的是真话
Looks like Selina was telling the truth.
我不想说死人坏话
Look, I don't want to speak ill of the dead,
但是这两个混蛋罪有应得
but these asshats had it coming.
这两个混蛋是专业纵火犯
These asshats were professional arsonists.
有人雇了他们
Somebody hired them.
为什么针对韦恩集团
Why Wayne Enterprises?
谁管呢
Who cares, all right?
有个疯子纵火小妞
There's a freaky firefly chick
正拿着个喷火器逍遥法外呢
on the loose with a flamethrower.
我们从那里入手吧
Let's start there.
哈利路亚
Hallelujah.
你好  布奇
Hello, Butch.
抱歉让你久等了
Sorry to keep you waiting.
我就是过来看看
I just wanted to check in,
看一切是否顺利
see how things were going.
有什么不满意的吗
Any complaints?
没有  先生  我感觉特别好
No. No, sir. I'm fine like a bottle of wine.
那就好
Good.
你在这里前途无量
You have a real future here.
你勤奋努力  一心为主  忠心耿耿
You are a hard worker, and you're loyal to a fault.
过奖了  老大
Thank you, boss.
可惜不是对我忠心
If only you were loyal to me.
我...
I, uh...
我听不懂你说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
行了  布奇  给自己留点尊严吧
Come on, Butch. Have some dignity.
我知道你在干什么
I know what you were doing.
你是在找企鹅的母亲吧
You were looking for Penguin's mother, weren't you?
手这招真妙
The hand was a nice touch.
差点被你骗过去了
Almost fooled me.
企鹅怎么说服你那么做的
How on earth did Penguin get you to do that?
我是他的仆人
I'm his servant.
他说什么  我就得做什么
I have to obey him in all things.
企鹅在你身上动手脚了啊
Penguin's done a number on you, huh?
控制了你的精神
Tinkered with your wiring.
也许我们能帮上忙
Perhaps we can help.
塔比
Tabby?
塔比  能请你过来下吗
Tabby, could you come here, please?
企鹅给这个可怜人洗脑了
Penguin has brainwashed this poor soul.
能帮他吗
Can we help?
乐意至极
Be my pleasure.
好吧  我们...
All right, let-let's...
我们先谈谈  好好谈谈吧
let's talk about this. Can we talk about this?
别冲动
Take it easy.
你要干什么
What are you doing?
放松
Relax.
我们就是想帮帮你
We just want to help.
你们俩慢慢玩吧
I'll leave you two to it.
别忘了  一小时后开晚饭
Uh, remember, dinner's in an hour.
我们布下了警戒线
We've set up a perimeter.
她跑不远
She can't have gotten far.
还派人在塞琳娜·凯尔的住处守着了
And we're sitting on Selina Kyle's place.
有新消息就通知我
Keep me posted.
布莉姬特·派克一直遭受虐待
Bridgit Pike was abused her whole life,
被迫放火
forced to set those fires.
我答应我的线人  会保她周全
I promised my informant I would keep her safe.
不是你说卢克·加勒特还是个孩子吗
Weren't you the one saying that Luke Garrett was just a kid?
我们要替他讨回公道
That we owe him justice?
我是这么说了
I know that's what I said.
你说得对
And you were right.
她杀了他
And now she killed him.
现在她又背上了两条人命
Now she has two more dead bodies on her.
所以我不管她有什么苦衷之类的
So I don't care about the hows and the whys and the boo-hoos.
你不能乱许下无法遵守的承诺
You don't make promises you can't keep.
找到她  抓到她
You find her and you take her down.
明白了吗
Clear?
是  长官
Yes, sir.
你在这上面看鸟的时间加起来得有好几年了
We must've spent years up here, watching these birds.
还记得米奇·斯拉特喊我们孤儿杂种
Remember when Mickey Slattery called us orphan bastards
我们想把他推下屋顶那次吗
and we tried to throw him off the roof?
警察就守在我家外面
The cops are outside my place.
你得离开这里
You need to get out of town.
我不怕他们
I'm not scared of them.
布莉姬特  我知道你对你哥哥们做了什么
Bridgit, I know what you did to your brothers.
虽然他们也是活该  但是
Not that they didn't deserve it, but...
没想到啊
I was surprised.
凯尔烧得很旺  但乔烧得最亮
Cale flamed up good, but it was Joe who burned the brightest.
你口气都不像自己了
You don't sound like yourself.
我不再是原来的我了
I'm not myself anymore.
我自由了
I'm free.
就像你说的那样
Just like you told me I was.
你打算怎么办
So what are you gonna do?
我要去找其余的那些
I'm gonna go after the rest of them.
其余的谁
The rest of who?
那些混蛋  恶霸
The pervs and the bullies.
那些伤害我们这种人的人
The ones who hurt people like us.
没有谁找过我麻烦  伤害过我
No one's ever gone after me or hurt me.
得了吧
Yeah, right.
首要规则
Rule number one:
照顾好首要人物
look after number one.
就是你
That's you.
别发疯  否则你会害死自己
Don't be crazy, or you'll get yourself killed.
别担心我  塞琳娜
Don't worry about me, Selina.
-我本来就该这么做  -布莉姬特
- This is what I was meant to do. - Bridgit,
求你  别这样
please, don't do this.
很高兴有人在乎我
It's nice to have someone who cares about me.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我才不在乎
I don't care.
我就是觉得你在犯傻  但是
I just think you're being dumb. But...
祝你好运
good luck.
回头见
I'll see you around.
敬杯酒
A toast.
抱歉
I'm so sorry.
临时出了点事
Something came up last minute.
我刚刚说到
As I was saying:
敬家人
To family.
说到底  家人才是最重要的
In the end, it's all that matters.
家人
Family.
希望  将来
I hope, in time,
你也能把我们当做家人  布鲁斯
you'll come to think of us as family, Bruce.
谢谢
Thank you.
我已经挺久没有
It's-it's been some time since I had a...
吃过这样一顿饭了
a meal like this.
跟女生一起吃吗
You mean with girls?
你该经常过来
You should come over more often.
我们可以一起玩玩
We can, like, hang out or whatever.
好啊
I'd like that.
看他们多可爱
Look how cute they are.
真想一口把他们吃下去
Don't you just want to eat them?
塔比莎  别吓唬他们
Tabitha, leave the young people alone.
他们就是很可爱嘛
Well, they are cute.
他们自己也知道
And they know it.
这是我吃过的最棒的土豆泥
These were the best mashed potatoes I have ever had.
我肯定要胖起来了
I swear, I'm gonna get plump.
很高兴你这么有胃口
I like that you have an appetite.
够了  我要被你宠坏了
Stop it, you're spoiling me.
没够  我就想宠坏你
I won't stop it. I want nothing more than to spoil you.
爱德
Ed.
好强势啊
So forceful.
我还有事想告诉你
There's something else I want to tell you.
我...
I just...
我不想把你吓跑
I don't want to scare you away.
没事  你什么都可以跟我说
Please, tell me anything.
不用有所保留
Do not hold back.
柯丽丝汀
Kristen...
我好喜欢你
...I like you very much.
我对你也有一样的感觉
I... I feel the same way about you.
还有
And, um...
And...
尼格玛先生
Mr. Nygma,
那边是你的卧室吗
is that your bedroom over there?
是啊
Why, yes, it is.
戈登  有电话找你
Gordon, phone call for you.
我是戈登
This is Gordon.
你还记得你的承诺吗
Do you remember your promise?
是的
Yes.
我想我知道她会去哪
I think I know where she's going.
别这样
No, no please!
快走
Go, go! Go!
Go, go!
快走
Go, go! Go!
走啊
Come on!
好了  今晚不要有人受伤
All right, no one gets hurt tonight.
我们遵守规章  注意安全
We follow protocols and stay safe.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
别动
Freeze!
手举起来
Hands in the air!
别开枪
Hold your fire!
布莉姬特·派克
Bridgit Pike!
别过来
Stay away!
我叫吉姆·戈登
My name's Jim Gordon.
我知道你哥哥们对你做了什么
I know what your brothers did to you.
我知道你并不希望发生这一切的
I know you didn't mean for any of this to happen.
你什么都不知道
You don't know anything!
把你的武器放下  跟我走
You put your weapon down and come with me,
我能帮你
I can help you.
你有地方可以去
There are places you can go.
我才不要进监狱
I'm not going to jail!
你还是未成年
You're a juvenile.
我们可以商量
We can work something out.
等等
Wait, wait!
别开火
I said hold your fire!
布莉姬特
Bridgit!
住手
Stop!
找掩护
Take cover!
布莉姬特  等等
Bridgit! Wait!
很高兴我们能单独谈会儿
I'm glad we have a moment alone.
我有事要跟你商量
There is something I need to discuss.
韦恩集团的一名高管被报失踪了
An executive at Wayne Enterprises has been reported missing:
希德·邦德斯洛
Sid Bunderslaw.
你认识他吗
Do you know him?
是的
Yes.
我们见过几次
We've met several times.
怎么回事
What happened?
没人知道
No one knows.
但看上去情况不妙
But it doesn't look good.
你怎么听到消息的
How did you hear?
这么说吧  我有身居高位的朋友
Let's just say I have friends in high places,
而且我一直在密切关注
and I've been following the goings-on
韦恩集团的动向
at Wayne Enterprises very closely.
你都发现了什么
What have you learned?
你父亲是个好人
That your father was a good man.
甚至可以说伟大
A great man, even.
尽管如此
But in spite of that,
他公司里还是有坏事发生
bad things happened at his company.
很不幸  我想你是对的
Unfortunately, I think you're right.
我看得出你是个早熟的孩子
I can tell you're very mature for your age.
已经准备好直面你公司的问题了
Ready to tackle the problems of your company head-on.
但你会需要帮助
But you'll need help.
等我当选了市长
Once I'm mayor,
我很乐意帮助你
I would very much like to be that person.
谢谢
Thank you...
盖勒文先生
Mr. Galavan.
多谢了
I-I appreciate it.
布奇
Butch.
-怎么了  -我找到你母亲了
- What has happened? - I found your mother.
-在哪  -码头的一间仓库
- Where? - In a warehouse down by the port.
但他们发现我在找了
But they caught me looking.
你个笨蛋  如果他们杀了我妈妈
You half-wit! If they kill my mother...!
他们不知道我来了
Look, they don't know I'm here.
那个母夜叉  想慢慢折磨我
The tigerlady, she wanted to take her time with me,
于是把我铐了起来  我自己逃脱了
so she chained me up and I got out.
我们得马上去
We gotta go now.
嗯  好
Yes. Yes, yes.
很好  布奇
Good, Butch.
你干的很好
You've done well.
你的忠心会得到丰厚报答
Your loyalty will be rewarded handsomely.
我发誓
I swear it.
是  老大
Yes, boss.
休息一会儿吧
Rest here for a minute,
我去集结手下
and I'll go gather the troops.
你多大了
How old are you?
已经能冲你开枪了  如果你在想这个的话
Old enough to shoot you, if that's what you're thinking.
不  我不是在想那个
No, that's not what I was thinking.
你不用拿枪指着我
You don't have to point the gun at me.
我不会伤害你的
I'm not gonna hurt you.
你当然不会
Damn right you're not.
我叫小莱
My name is Lee.
我知道你叫什么
I know what your name is.
你叫什么
What's your name?
你还挺可爱
You're cute.
就医生来说
For a doctor.
谢谢  你也挺可爱
Thanks. You're cute.
就个黑帮分子来说
For a gangster.
塞琳娜
Hi, Selina.
抱歉了  小莱
Sorry about this, Lee.
没事啦
Oh, hey, no problem.
怎么样
So...
布莉姬特没事吧
is Bridgit okay?
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
她恐怕活不成了
She's not gonna make it.
你答应要帮她的
You said that you'd help her.
我尽力了  塞琳娜  真的
I tried, Selina. I tried.
但她不愿束手就擒
But she didn't want to go quietly.
我觉得她就希望是这样的结局
I think she wanted it to end this way.
听我说
Look...
-塞琳娜  -别碰我  别碰我
- Selina... - Don't touch me. Don't touch me.
我知道关于布莉姬特你说的是实话
I know you were telling the truth about Bridgit.
是她哥哥们叫她这么做的
That her brothers put her up to this.
我需要知道是谁雇了他们
I need to know who hired them.
我说了  我不知道
I already told you I don't know.
-我还是不信  -你管呢
- And I still don't believe you. - What do you care?
你才不在乎我们这样的人
You don't care about people like us.
你又不会去找你小伙伴的麻烦
It's not like you're really gonna go after your little friend.
我的小伙伴
My friend?
你是指企鹅吗
Do you mean Penguin?
他为什么要纵火
Why would he set those fires?
-这没道理  -你自己去问他吧
- That doesn't make any sense. - Ask him yourself.
我不想再跟你说话了
I'm done talking to you.
我就不该
I should have never
信个警察
trusted a cop.
我想帮她的  但是结果不如人意
I tried to help her, it just went a different way.
你就是这么形容一个人的死吗
Is that what you call it when someone dies?
你就这么安慰自己吗
Is that what you tell yourself?
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
随便了
Whatever.
你真好
You're so sweet.
柯丽丝汀  怎么了
Kristen, what's the matter?
我好怕
I'm scared.
怕什么
Of what?
汤姆·多尔蒂
Of Tom Dougherty.
他曾跟我说
He used to tell me...
如果他看见我跟别的男人在一起
if he ever saw me with another man,
他会杀了我
he would kill me.
我很害怕他回来后会怎么样
I'm terrified of what will happen when he comes back.
-你不用担心那个了  -不
- You don't need to worry about that. - No...
你不了解他
you don't know him.
他是个...禽兽
He is... A monster.
听我说
Listen to me.
你不用担心汤姆·多尔蒂了
You do not need to worry about Tom Dougherty.
你真好
You are sweet.
但你不是个斗士
But... you're not a fighter.
你是打不过他的
You couldn't possibly take him on.
相信我  都解决好了
Trust me, it's been taken care of.
什么意思
What does that mean?
前不久  我和他起过争执
Some time ago, he and I had an altercation.
我叫他对你放尊重点
I asked him to treat you with more respect.
天呐
Oh, my God.
他说他会按自己喜欢的方式待你  还打了我
And he said he would treat you any way he liked and he assaulted me.
天呐
Oh, my God!
总之  长话短说
So, anyhow, long story short...
我杀了他
I killed him.
爱德
Oh, Ed, that's...
你还真差点骗到我了
You had me going for a minute, there.
就在你公寓外的高架列车下面
It was outside of your apartment under the elevated train.
我捅了他  他死了
I stabbed him and he died.
爱德  别闹了
Ed, that's not funny.
我没闹
I'm not being funny.
T·多尔蒂
"T. Dougherty."
你现在信我了吗
Do you believe me now?
天呐
Oh, my God.
怎么了
What's wrong?
-你去哪  -你怎么能
- Where are you going? - How could you?
-别这样  坐下  -别碰我
- No, please, sit down. - Don't touch me!
求你让我解释
Would you please let me explain?
没什么好解释的  我都不知道你是什么人
There is nothing to explain. I don't even know who you are.
不对  你是个杀人犯
No, that's wrong. You are a murderer.
他是个禽兽  你自己也说了
He was a monster! You said so!
他虐待你
He was abusing you.
我居然还爱上你了  你个变态
I can't believe I even fell for you, you sicko.
我才不变态  我爱你  我是为你那么做的
I'm not sick. I love you. I did it for you.
我以前对你的一切看法都是对的
Everything I ever thought about you, I was right.
我真该去检查我的脑袋
I should have my head examined.
别那么说
Don't say that.
慢着  你怎么会在我家外面
Wait, what were you doing outside my house?
我担心你
I was worried for you.
你是在跟踪我  你是个变态
You were stalking me. You are a psychopath.
才不是  我不是那种人
That is not true! That's not who I am.
别那么说我
Don't say that about me.
你要进监狱了
You are going to prison
你会在那里遭到各种虐待
where they will do horrible things to you.
那都是你活该
Things that you deserve.
别对我说那种话
Don't say that to me.
不  放手  别碰我
No, let go. Don't touch me!
放开我  你个怪胎
Let go of me, you freak.
请别那么喊我
Please don't call me that.
救命
Help!
听我说
Listen to me.
我并不是你想的那样
I am not the man that you think I am.
我绝不会伤害你的
I would never do anything to hurt you.
我杀他是因为他打你
I had to kill him because he hit you.
你明白吗
Do you understand that?
我是为你做的
I did it for you.
我保证我今后绝不会做任何伤害你的事
I promise I will never do anything to hurt you ever again.
我爱你
I love you.
我从第一眼看到你就爱上了你
I've loved you since the first moment that I saw you.
柯丽丝汀  柯丽丝汀
Kristen? Kristen?
不不不
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no... no, no.
不不  不要
Oh, no, plea...
不
Oh, no.
不不不
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
不要
Please.
不要啊
Please, no.
不
No. No.
No!
不
这女孩真惨啊
Damn, this girl looks rough.
他们对外宣称她死了
They tell people she dead.
那是谎言
But that's a lie.
听说她穿的衣服融在她身上了
I heard the suit she was wearing melted to her.
说她防火了
Say she's fireproof.
拜托
Come on.
是啊  防火喽
Yeah, man-- fireproof.
所以他们把她送这儿来了
That's why they sent her down here,
跟其他那些怪物待在一起
with the rest of the monsters.
好进行测试
For testing.
印第安山
韦恩集团分部